[♪ theme music playing]
THE HUSBAND
THIS SERIES IS FICTITIOUS
CHILDREN WERE FILMED SAFELY
GEN AI WAS USED IN SELECT SCENES
[elevator dings]
Don't worry.
Relax and just be yourself.
Do your thing.
KANG TAEJU'S MASTER'S THESIS
ADVISOR: PROFESSOR KIM JONGHYEON
SEYEON UNIVERSITY
DEPARTMENT OF NEUROLOGY, KANG TAEJU
[door opens]
-Hey, we're here.
-Hello.
[Seyun's mother, Taeju chuckle]
Hello. My name is Kang Taeju.
Pleasure to meet you.
Hi, nice to meet you. [chuckles]
-Good to meet you.
-[chuckles]
We're pretty high up, huh?
Much higher than you'd imagine.
Oh, yes.
Glad you made it all the way up.
-Well, let's have a seat.
-Okay.
-Make yourself at home.
-Thank you.
[♪ soft classical music playing]
[door opens, closes]
-Hmm? [chuckles]
-[Dr. Ko sipping drink]
[sighs]
You know, Seyun talks about you a lot.
I heard you are a doctor.
Where do you work?
Well, I'm currently a neurosurgeon
at Seyeon University Hospital.
Oh… Seyeon University?
[inhales sharply]
The head of Neurosurgery is
Kim Jonghyeon, is it?
Yeah, it is Dr. Kim.
[Dr. Ko] Hmm.
I used to be his professor.
Ah.
On his first day in the OR, his scalpel
hand was shaking like a leaf. [laughs]
How was your first time?
Weren't you nervous
during your first surgery?
Well, I was really nervous too.
I still get nervous.
[laughs]
So, neurosurgery.
What's your specialty?
I specialize in spinal cord surgery.
Quite a tricky field you chose.
Mmm. Spinal cord.
One slight slip of the hand,
and the patient may never walk again.
Yes, that's why I try to be
as cautious as possible at all times.
STYLE
::cue()
[Dr. Ko] Great attitude.
Once you make a mistake,
there's no way to redeem yourself.
Right.
Tell me, what do your parents do?
My family runs a small restaurant.
My father passed away
when I was in high school.
Oh…
[chuckles]
Still, I'm sure your mother is very proud
to have such a great doctor of a son.
Oh, yes. Thank you for saying that.
What kind of restaurant is it?
Dad, can you stop with the questions?
No, it's fine.
Actually, it's a chueotang place.
That's her specialty.
Oh. [laughs]
Wow, it must have been
quite tough for her.
Med school isn't exactly cheap.
It couldn't have been easy
to pay that off. [laughs]
Actually, Dad, Taeju entered and graduated
top of his class,
never losing his scholarship.
Oh, is that right?
[Seyun] What I'm saying is,
his mother doesn't have
to break her back anymore.
Wow. [chuckles] That's quite something.
Incredible indeed. [laughs]
Seyun.
You've brought home
a very fine young man. Hmm? [chuckling]
So, would you say he has your approval?
That's not for me to decide.
What matters is that you like him.
[chuckling]
[stammers]
Thank you, Mr. Ko.
I should be the one thanking you.
[Dr. Ko, Taeju chuckling]
-[exclaims]
-[gasps]
Doctor.
Did…
Did I really just move?
Yes, you did.
[stammers] Can you feel your legs now?
[relative] It's been 10 years.
-[crying] Minseok.
-Mom.
-Doctor, thank you so much. Thank you.
-Thank you. Thank you, Doctor.
[relatives crying, exclaiming]
[door beeps]
-How's everyone doing?
-Hey.
I heard about Minseok.
You finally saw movement.
What? Oh, yeah.
Wow.
[doctors applauding]
I told you. I knew he could do it.
Dr. Kang, that is remarkable.
I couldn't have done it alone.
It was a team effort.
Congratulations.
[laughs]
Thank you.
STYLE
::cue()
[Seyun] Do you want some of this, Hayun?
You cute little thing. [chuckles]
[Hayun] Mommy, this is for you.
-Well, thank you. This looks lovely.
-Sure.
[chuckles]
What's been going on with you lately?
-Why?
-You're smiling.
You look happy.
Ah. You think so?
Yes.
I did surgery on this patient
who couldn't move for a decade,
and he moved his legs.
-Are you serious?
-Yeah.
His parents were so happy
that they started crying.
I think that was the first time
I realized I could give someone hope.
I guess I needed to find
that hope for myself.
I wanted to believe
that my work makes a difference.
Thanks.
For what?
For everything.
[chuckles]
[chuckling]
[medical equipment beeping]
How's the blood loss?
[nurse 1] Holding steady at 50 ccs.
All right, looking good.
Debridement is complete.
-Open the scaffold.
-Okay.
[nurse 1] Dr. Kang?
Let me double-check the label.
Is this the scaffold for Park Dohyeon?
Yes, it's labeled for Park Dohyeon.
Is there a problem?
NAME: PARK DOHYEON
[♪ tense music playing]
Nothing. Let's proceed.
Both in their sixties,
but the pigmentation…
It's significantly different.
STYLE
::cue()
[♪ tense music playing]
AUTOLOGOUS MSC CULTURE &
DIFFERENTIATION ANALYSIS REPORT
The cellular alignment is off too.
There's a massive discrepancy
in the differentiation rate.
[sighs]
PARK DOHYEON
DATE OF BIRTH: MAY 24, 1963
KIM HOJIN
DATE OF BIRTH: DECEMBER 9, 1964
These are both autologous cells, right?
So why?
[music ends]
LEE SEONGUK (70/M)
KIM JEONGHUI (31/F), KIM HUN (50/M)
[sighs]
[Dr. Ko] Dr. Kang doesn't usually come
down to the lab this time of day, does he?
[Jeongsoo] No.
He's usually tied up in the OR.
[Dr. Ko] Mmm.
[Jeongsoo] You didn't have to
come down here yourself, sir.
[chuckles]
I heard Dr. Kang personally verified
the label on the Park Dohyeon case today.
Yes, so I haven't laid my hands on it yet,
in case he takes notice.
Well, you can't just let it sit there.
Tomorrow's patient
is Chairman Lee Seonguk of Jeonghan Group.
He's a VIP, which means
all eyes are on us for this one,
so we'll need to be extra prepared.
Let me take a look myself.
I don't want any loose ends.
-Let's verify it now.
-Yes, understood.
[Dr. Ko] What about the logs?
[Jeongsoo] I've already backdated
the culture logs to match.
The entire future of this hospital
is riding on this project.
There can't be a single mistake.
Yes, I understand.
[Taeju] What's going on here?
Dr. Kang.
LEE SEONGUK (70/M)
Wait…
What am I looking at?
Why are there two stem cell samples
from the same patient?
[♪ tense music playing]
Uh…
Dr. Ha.
[Jeongsoo] That-That's…
These are fetal stem cells.
They were harvested from an aborted fetus.
What did you just say?
STYLE
::cue()
THE HUSBAND
[Dr. Ko] Stop this procedure
and get Chairman Kim on the table first.
This patient is critical.
It's an emergency cauda equina case.
Don't you hear me?
I don't give a damn what it is!
Do you have any idea how much Chairman Kim
has poured into this facility?
-Please get out.
-What?
I said, get the hell out of here!
This is what I get
for letting you into my family.
So you're asking to have her
operated on at our hospital?
That criminal?
We have to find out
who kidnapped Seyun and why.
If she dies, we'll never get
to the truth, Father.
No way.
[Dosik] I understand this situation
may be quite upsetting for you,
but he does have a point.
I'm the director of this hospital!
Plus, do you think anyone
would take on this surgery?
No doctor here would be up for it!
I'm doing this surgery.
I'll operate on you.
Don't worry, I'm a doctor.
It's my job and duty to save lives.
But…
after what you did to my wife…
When I think about that…
Maybe you're not worth saving.
I could say the same thing
about that father-in-law of yours.
[officer] Mr. Kang, you have a visitor.
Hello, I'm Attorney Choi Daehyeong.
Ms. Ko hired me
to represent you in court, Mr. Kang.
-Seyun did that?
-Yes.
Your detention hearing is
scheduled for this afternoon.
Look, it's an uphill battle.
But fortunately, Ms. Ko submitted
letters asking for leniency
and no prosecution.
The details are solid,
and they paint a clear picture
of why you were forced into this position.
If we can convince the judge
you're not a flight risk
or a threat to the evidence,
we can push for release pending trial.
The warrant was denied.
Choi, give him his belongings.
Here.
We're not done here.
We'll call you back if we need you.
If you don't answer,
you can get arrested again.
So keep your phone on.
I'll be watching you, Mr. Kang.
Yeah, you do that.
Just try not to get in my way
while you're at it.
STYLE
::cue()
WOORI TOGETHER MEDICAL CENTER
[♪ tense music playing]
7 KIM GYEONGAE, POST-OP, NPO
7 KIM GYEONGAE
[stammering] Dr. Kang!
Hey.
What are you doing right now?
Potassium chloride?
Giving undiluted IV potassium chloride
would cause hyperkalemia
and cardiac arrest.
You're a doctor, so surely you knew that.
Dr. Ha Jeongsoo.
I knew all along that she was a patient
at our hospital, and that you were
her attending physician.
Can you not move it?
What about your back?
[screaming]
-It hurts.
-Doctor.
We found these meds on the desk.
DEPARTMENT: SURGERY
ATTENDING PHYSICIAN: HA JEONGSOO
Run her info.
See if she's gotten a scan
at this hospital before.
[typing]
PATIENT INFORMATION
NAME: KIM GYEONGAE
[doctor] Yes, we've got her MRI
from six months ago.
Why would this woman,
who was your patient…
kidnap my wife?
The Dr. Ha I know
would never do anything like this.
Who is it?
Who's calling the shots?
[stammering]
Is it Director Ko Dongchan?
[Dr. Ko] How are you going
to do this surgery?
I'm going to do it by the book.
"By the book"?
Sure, you should, as a doctor.
But not all life is of equal value.
That woman is not a patient.
She put your wife in danger
and tried to take her life.
RESTRICTED ACCESS
[Dr. Ko] The OR is a strange place.
Even if you prepare
for every possible scenario,
you still run into unexpected situations.
[Taeju] The immediate crisis is over,
and her vitals are steady for now.
[Dr. Ko] Good job.
Well done,
STYLE
::cue()
saving that woman.
Dr. Ha. A moment.
It's him, right?
Dr. Ko,
you,
and this woman.
What is the connection there?
[scoffs, stammers]
How am I supposed to know?
Why did you try to kill this woman?
I don't know.
I honestly don't know anything.
Tell me.
I know you know.
I don't know, man.
I was only doing what I was told.
[nurse 2] Oh my! What…
[objects clatter on floor]
Dr. Kang, what are you doing here?
I'm here to check on the patient
I operated on. Are you okay?
Yeah.
I was just about to leave.
Can you wake him up?
[sighs] Okay.
Isn't it so tense
at the hospital these days?
Is it?
Well, nobody talks about it,
but everyone thinks it's weird.
They're only keeping it quiet
because it's about Ms. Ko and Dr. Kang--
[shouts, exclaims]
[exclaims] Geez.
That was Dr. Ha, wasn't it?
What's wrong with him?
-Darn it.
-Beats me.
KO DONGCHAN, DIRECTOR
[music ends]
[Seyun's mother] Scary, isn't it?
Mom.
We took him in as part
of our family, and now this.
How could he do something like that?
How are you feeling?
Maybe you should go back to the hospital.
I'm fine, Mom.
I just want to rest at home.
Okay.
We should get that fixed soon.
STYLE
::cue()
SEOKGI CHUEOTANG
Mom, I'll finish up here.
You should head home.
[sighs]
[door opens]
Sorry, we're…
[gasps] Taeju.
Hi, Mom.
[shakily] Where…
[♪ sentimental music playing]
I'm sorry.
Save your apology for later.
It's fine.
As long as you're okay.
Man, you look rough.
-Are you okay?
-Yeah, I'm fine.
What about Seyun? Is she okay too?
Yeah, she's fine. She's safe.
Oh, thank goodness.
[crying] I'm so relieved.
[sighing]
I see.
And so, have you talked to Seyun?
Well, we haven't really had a chance
to talk things through yet.
Why not?
It's just… [chuckles]
I don't want any more misunderstandings.
Surely, it can't get any worse.
You even shot up her parents' house,
-so how could it--
-Taeyeong.
[sighs]
How are you going to set things straight?
Just sit down and talk to her.
You can't avoid it forever.
Not yet. Well…
There are a few things
I need to verify first.
I can't really clear the air
with Seyun until I do.
Taeju.
Yes?
Look, I don't know the ins and outs
of your marriage,
but don't drag this out.
The longer you let this sit,
the more difficult it will be
to set things straight.
And at that point, it'll be too late.
Whatever you're going to do,
don't take too long.
You understand?
Yeah.
Why don't you stay the night?
Okay.
-Here.
-Oh, no, I'm good.
Let me pour you one.
[laughs]
What's so funny?
You're just so fickle, aren't you?
What do you mean?
I mean, at first,
you couldn't live without her,
and then you couldn't stand
living with her.
And now, you're putting
your life on the line to save the woman
you couldn't stand living with.
[laughs]
That's pretty fickle, isn't it?
STYLE
::cue()
Do you know why I wanted
to end things with Seyun?
Why?
I didn't want her to be lonely
or in pain anymore.
Why are you getting all deep on me now?
Make it make sense.
I thought it was the right thing to do.
To let her off the leash.
But I think I was wrong.
I'm done running away now.
Usually, these types of crimes
are committed by a lone wolf,
but in this case,
we're looking at a married couple.
MARRIED COUPLE IN ON THE CRIME
Isn't that utterly shocking?
It's beyond disturbing.
And what's even more shocking?
They barely even know me.
They've never even talked to me,
but the second
something like this happens,
they all start running their mouths
like they know all about me.
[TV host 1]
…that he was always kind and polite.
And yet, he's accused
of committing these heinous acts.
He was a kind teacher by day
but a depraved criminal by night.
He was living an absolute double life.
[TV host 2] Exactly.
That's what makes it so terrifying.
Don't you think so?
He didn't fit the profile of a criminal.
No sinister looks, no red flags.
JANG BONE-BROTH SUNDAEGUK
-Hello.
-[owner] Hi, how are you? [chuckles]
Oh, dear.
[chuckles]
You're back again. [laughs]
-Enjoy.
-Thank you.
Oh, hey. You're here.
[chuckles] I wanted to grab a bite
before heading home.
Well, I'm glad you came.
Oh, right. Ever since you fixed it,
that machine hasn't acted up once.
It's all thanks to you.
[chuckling] Oh, come on, it was nothing.
So, one gukbap?
-Yeah.
-Okay, give me a moment. [laughing]
[sighs]
-[Dosik] Detective Oh!
-Yes, sir.
FORENSICS
Darn.
[♪ ominous music playing]
What the hell is this?
[Hyeonsu]
Wow, this guy is completely nuts.
[sighs]
Collect every luminol-positive bloodstain
in the basement,
and send them to the NFS.
Request blood analysis
and DNA comparison too.
Yes, sir.
We don't know what else we'll find,
so search every inch.
Yes, sir.
What's that?
It's a cell phone.
It was under the fridge.
-The fridge?
-Yeah.
STYLE
::cue()
SEOKGI CHUEOTANG
CLOSED FOR TODAY
Dr. Ha. A moment.
Dr. Kang!
You didn't have to
come down here yourself, sir.
I heard Dr. Kang personally verified
the label on the Park Dohyeon case today.
The entire future of this hospital
is riding on this project.
What about the logs?
I've already backdated
the culture logs to match.
What's going on here?
Dr. Kang.
[Taeju] What am I looking at?
Why are there two stem cell samples
from the same patient?
Dr. Ha.
Take a sip.
What's going on?
[sighs]
I wish you hadn't found out.
Although I did think
that you would find out someday.
Switching out a patient's
stem cell sample with a fetus's?
Why would you do this?
There are limits
to stem cells from an adult.
You may be good,
but you were far beneath
the success rate we're aiming for.
However, after we switched them out,
it was a different story.
You did the surgeries, so you should know
STYLE
::cue()
what we've accomplished.
The patients consented to the procedure
thinking it was their own stem cells.
This is completely illegal, Father.
Those illegal procedures
helped people regain movement
and stand on their own two feet.
What do you make of those results?
You've seen them.
The faces they make after the procedure.
Those people had given up,
but now, they're hopeful
and excited about the future.
Couldn't you just
let them have that hope?
That is not hope.
Any hope that's built on a lie
is bound to fall apart.
Knowingly giving them false hope…
That's not hope. It's deception.
Please count me out of this project.
What about Seyun?
What will you do about her?
[steady beeping]
[door opens, closes]
[sighs]
Can you check
Ms. Kim Gyeongae's vitals every hour?
Okay, I will.
But Dr. Choi.
How long will she be at our hospital?
Why?
I mean, it's just uncomfortable.
Everyone feels that way.
Well, she's still a patient.
She has to recover.
I'm going to head home.
Let me know when she wakes up.
Okay.
STYLE
::cue()
[phone buzzing]
INCOMING CALL
GRANDDAUGHTER
[buzzing continues]
Grandma! Why can't I reach you?
Who are you?
Catch your breath now.
Have a seat.
Don't you remember me?
Sweetheart, can you set his table?
Okay, Grandma.
Your grandmother's told me all about you.
-Nice to meet you.
-Likewise.
You know Woori Together Medical Center?
She works as a nurse there.
Ah!
Yeah, I've been there.
She helps me out
whenever she can, after her shift.
She's not like
the other young people these days.
That's amazing. You must be proud of her.
What are you doing here?
[breathing heavily]
Where's my grandma?
Your grandma?
She's gone on a trip.
She was in a hurry,
so she wanted me to watch the place.
But that's her phone.
Oh, yeah. She must've forgotten.
Where is my grandma?
I said, she's on a trip.
Why would she suddenly go on a trip
without even telling me?
Guess she didn't feel like telling you.
Where's my grandma?
Where is she?
I'm going to call the cops.
If you do, I feel like I might…
forget where your grandma is.
My grandma…
Is she safe?
We'll see.
It depends on how you do.
[Taeju] Anyway, that being said…
I want you to get rid of my wife.
[Manhui] What? What did you say?
[Taeju] Get rid of my wife.
Ms. Ko.
How does that make you feel?
I know this is fake.
There's no way he said anything like that.
I know you don't want to believe it.
But hey.
You already know
that your husband doesn't love you.
No!
That video. It's all a misunderstanding.
I can explain all of it.
I'm telling you the truth.
Please. Please just believe me.
Seyun.
Seyun, come on.
Seyun. Come on. Please.
Seyun.
Seyun, can you hear me?
Hey, are you okay?
[Dr. Ko] What did you say?
What?
What are you saying?
Ugh. Calm down.
I can't understand a word!
What?
Kang Taeju was there?
Why are you telling me this now?
You know what a huge problem
you've caused?
STYLE
::cue()
Where are you right now?
I'll take care of it myself.
Just come to the hospital.
No.
Just come back to the hospital!
[clicks tongue]
Taeju?
[♪ ballad playing]
[Dr. Ko] What about Seyun?
What will you do about her?
What if the whole world finds out?
A father who's a criminal,
the hospital that turned a blind eye,
and the husband at the center of it all.
Seyun will have to shoulder all of that.
Whether you do the surgery or not,
that's your call.
But it won't be you who pays the price.
It will be Seyun.
What her life will be like after that…
Have you thought about that?
[♪ song continues]
[song ends]
I'm here to check on her.
[officer] Okay.
[medical equipment beeping]
It's me.
Her BP and heart rate seem normal,
and her breathing's stable.
She's not conscious yet,
but she seems stable.
[sighs]
Keep an eye on her.
Okay.
Oh, and one more thing.
Dr. Kang stopped by her room yesterday.
What are you…
I thought he was arrested.
I'm not sure what happened either.
I talked to another nurse,
and it seems he snuck in
while the police officer was asleep.
Tell me all the details.
Apparently, he said he came
to check on the patient
and then just left.
STYLE
::cue()
NEUROSURGERY
HA JEONGSOO
[breathing heavily]
INCOMING CALL
ILSEUNG CAPITAL
[phone buzzing]
CAPTAIN, MAJOR CRIMES UNIT 1
LIEUT. JANG DOSIK
Captain.
Yeah?
You should see this.
COME TO THE HOSPITAL
WE NEED TO TALK
"To the hospital?"
-Is that all?
-Yeah, everything else was wiped clean.
[sighs] Get Kim Gyeongae's phone
to Forensics now.
-We have to recover all of it.
-On it, sir.
She's been in touch
with someone in the hospital.
[tires screech]
[phone buzzes]
ILSEUNG CAPITAL: PAY BACK BY MORNING,
OR WE'LL SEE YOU AT YOUR GIRL'S PRESCHOOL
[sighs]
Darn, Kang Taeju.
If only he hadn't shown up.
Dr. Ha!
Oh, hi.
Working late tonight, Dr. Ha?
Uh, yeah.
Me too.
[tires screech]
[car alarm beeps]
[sighs] Dr. Ha!
How did this happen?
I told you to be cautious!
Dr. Ko?
[♪ tense music playing]
[stammers]
What the hell are you doing here?
I could ask you the same thing.
What are you doing here so late?
Oh, let me guess.
You're not here to see Dr. Ha, are you?
I'm the one asking questions.
What are you doing here?
I just had to check something.
"Check something"?
Yeah, it turns out
that woman, Kim Gyeongae,
was one of our patients.
And Dr. Ha was her attending physician.
Were you aware of that?
[scoffs]
So?
What are you getting at?
I caught him right before he injected
potassium chloride into her IV.
I barely stopped him.
What possible reason
could he have
to do such a thing to that woman?
That's what I wanted to know.
But she's unconscious,
and I have no clue where Dr. Ha is.
So I'm out of options.
Considering you're the hospital director,
I thought you might know a thing or two.
STYLE
::cue()
One of our patients…
Dr. Ha's patient
was one of Seyun's kidnappers.
Why on earth did she do that?
You should ask that
to that criminal of a woman.
Why are you asking me?
Sure, but don't you think
it's a bit weird?
That woman
seems to know so much about you.
[♪ tense music playing]
You've known Kim Gyeongae
all along, haven't you?
After what you did to my wife…
Maybe you're not worth saving.
I could say the same thing
about that father-in-law of yours.
That scumbag extending his own lifespan
by using those unborn babies.
She knew that you were using
stem cells from fetuses.
She knew all the details.
Isn't that why you tried to shut her up…
with the help of Dr. Ha?
Why did you try to kill this woman?
I don't know.
I honestly don't know anything.
I know you know.
I don't know, man.
I was only doing as I was told. Okay?
You and Kim Gyeongae.
What is the connection between you two?
The woman who knows the secret
behind the project
kidnapped my wife.
Is that really a coincidence?
So what?
Are you suggesting
that I had my own daughter kidnapped?
Did you not?
You've lost your mind.
Well…
Do you have any evidence?
You don't, do you?
If you want to know so badly,
ask that woman once she wakes up.
Either that
or ask Ha Jeongsoo,
wherever the hell he is.
[music ends]
CALLING
NS_HA JEONGSOO
[line ringing]
[sighs]
[ringing continues]
[ringing stops]
PARKING
[♪ tense music playing]
WING B, B3F
STYLE
::cue()
[line ringing]
[phone ringing in distance]
[distant ringing continues]
[ringing continues]
DIRECTOR KANG TAEJU
THE HUSBAND
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[Taeju] I wanted to check the applications
and selection records…
[Seyun] Is it related to my dad?
[Hyeonsu] About the phone
that Ha Jeongsoo had on him…
It's the same number
that contacted Kim Gyeongae.
I'll stay on Ms. Kim Gyeongae's case.
Both my husband and I
were just pawns in this game.
[Taeju] If someone actually tried
to have you killed through Dr. Ha…
Do you think that person
will leave you alone now?
[granddaughter] If someone ever finds out,
I'll be in huge trouble.
[Manhui] Today.
It'll be over today.
Translated by Hyun Sik Yoon